phones4u.co.uk 2011-12-31

# Phones 4u - Privacy Policy

We will treat all your personal information: 

Phones 4u Limited, who is the 'data controller' of all personal data provided by you through this website, will treat all your personal information: 

  * As confidential and will only disclose the same in the circumstances set out below; and, 
  * In accordance with data protection and privacy legislation from time to time in force in England and Wales. 

When you shop on this website, we will ask you to input personal details in order for us to identify you, such as your name, e-mail address, billing and delivery address, credit card or other payment information. We confirm that this information will be held by us in accordance with the registration we have with the Information Commissioner's office and collected lawfully in accordance to the Data Protection Act 1998. We will use your personal information for the following purposes: 

  * Processing your orders (including incomplete or failed orders) and conducting business with you; 
  * To administer this website; 
  * For statistical, market research and customer satisfaction purposes to improve this website and our services to you; 
  * If you have not objected during the registration process, to notify you of products, services or special offers that may be of interest to you, for example an Upgrade Reminder Service. 
  * If you have not objected during the registration process, to disclose to other members within our group of companies and also to other relevant third parties, who may contact you about their products or services that may be of interest to you; 

Subject to your rights of objection, you agree that personal information may be disclosed to other businesses within our group of companies and to reputable third parties who will help process your order or whose products or services may be of interest to you. In addition, you do not object to us, our group companies or third parties contacting you for the purposes set out above, whether this be by fax, telephone, e-mail, SMS or other electronic means or in writing and you consent to this activity for the purposes of the Privacy and Electronic Communications (EC Directive) Regulations 2003. 

You should be aware that if the police requests us or any other regulatory authority investigating suspected illegal activities to provide your personal information, we are entitled to do so. Objections to use of personal information for marketing purposes

If you have not objected during the registration process, but do not want us to: 

  * Contact you regarding products or services which may be of interest to you; or 
  * To transfer your data to group companies and third parties so that they can contact you about their products and services; 

##  Then please write to us at: 

Web Customer Services Team   
Osprey House  
Ore Close  
Lymedale Business Park  
Newcastle-under-Lyme  
Staffordshire  
ST5 9QD  
and notify us accordingly.

Subject to your rights of objection, you agree that personal information may be disclosed to other businesses within our group of companies and to reputable third parties who will help process your order. In addition, you do not object to us, our group companies or third parties contacting you for the purposes set out above, whether this be by fax, telephone, e-mail, SMS or in writing and you do not consider any of the above as being a breach of any of your rights under the Telecommunications (Data Protection and Privacy) Regulations 1999. 

You should be aware that if the police requests us or any other regulatory authority investigating suspected illegal activities to provide your personal information, we are entitled to do so.

## Cookies 

Like many other web sites we use Cookies on our site. Cookies can help a website to personalise your visit. A Cookie is a text-only string of information that a website transfers to the Cookie file of the browser on your computer's hard disk so that the website can, among other things, remember who you are. A Cookie will typically contain the name of the domain from which the Cookie has come, the "lifetime" of the Cookie, and a value, usually a randomly generated unique number. Three types of electronic access, storage and/or tracing devices are used on this website:- 

### Session Cookies:

which are temporary Cookies that remain in the cookie file of your browser until you leave the site. This information is not stored after you have left the site.

### Persistent cookies:

which remain in the Cookie file of your browser for much longer (though how long will depend on the lifetime of the specific cookie but this may be indefinitely or until deleted).

### Web Beacons:

which are electronic images known as Web Beacons (also called "clear gifs") that allow us to count the number of users who have visited these Web pages. 

Cookies cannot be used by themselves to identify you. However, if you are an existing customer and you have logged onto this site and identified yourself as a customer, we may be able to connect your personal information with your cookie information. 

How we use these electronic devices on our Website and what Information we collect.

### Session Cookies:

we use Session Cookies to allow you to carry information across pages of our site and avoid having to re-enter information, during that particular visit. This information will not be available next time you visit our website.

### Persistent Cookies:

we use Persistent Cookies to help us recognise you as a unique visitor when you next visit our website. The information stored may be recognised and used by our web-site next time you visit and we may use this information to personalise your visits and specifically tailor advertising and/or information directed toward you. This information may also be used to assist in the efficiency of the sign up process and to compile anonymous, aggregated statistics that allow us to understand how users use our website and to help us improve the structure of our website. Unless specifically deleted this information may be stored and accessed for an indefinite period of time.

We cannot identify you personally in this way and we do not collect or monitor your customer information in conjunction with your Cookie information][although we may collect and monitor your customer information in conjunction with your Cookie information.

### Web Beacons:

we use Web Beacons to collect only limited information including but not limited to, a Cookie number, which Web page you visited, the number of times you visited that Web page, the time and date you visited that Web page, the length of that visit and a description of the Web page which you visited and on which the Web Beacon resides. We use this information to compile anonymous, aggregated statistics that allow us to understand how users use our website and to help us improve the structure of our website. We can also use this information to recognise whether you have visited our Website before. Unless specifically deleted this information may be stored and accessed for an indefinite period of time.  

### Third party Cookies:

We use third-party advertising technology to serve our advertisements when you visit our website and sites upon which we advertise. This technology uses information about your visits to this website and the sites upon which we advertise, to serve our advertisements to you. In the course of serving our advertisements to you, a unique third-party cookie may be placed or recognized on your browser. In addition, we use Web beacons, provided by our third-party ad server, to help manage and optimize our online advertising. These Web beacons enable our ads server, on our behalf or on behalf of our agent, to recognize a browser's cookie when a browser visits this site, and to learn which banner ads bring users to our website. Our third-party ad server is performing its functions on our behalf or on behalf of our agent, and we may, directly or indirectly, instruct such ad server to enable other service providers to receive information about our site related to our online advertising.

### Disabling Cookies:

If you do not wish to accept our Cookies or Web Beacons you can decline Cookies and/or Web Beacons and/or refuse access to previously stored information by using your web Browser. The facilities within your web Browser to allow you to do this will vary from Browser to Browser but they may be found in the “Privacy” or “Cookies” section of the “Properties” menu of your Browser. If you require assistance in disabling Cookies you should refer to the "help" menu within your Browser. Please note however, that you may not be able to use all of the interactive features of our Website if Cookies and/or Web Beacons are disabled.
